Guide to the John Holker Papers GEN MSS 2092
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
John Holker papers
1777-1821, undated
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Holker, John, 1745-1822
GEN MSS 2092
10.5 Linear Feet (11 boxes)
The collection consists of correspondence, memoranda, accounts, and invoices relating to the activities of French diplomat and naval agent John Holker during the American Revolutionary War, as well as his private business ventures.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of William Smith Mason, 1935, with later acquisitions. Transferred from Sterling Memorial Library, 1984.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Correspondence and Other Papers, 1777-1821. II. Catalog Cards, undated.
John Holker (1745-1822)
John Holker was an English-born French diplomat, merchant, and enslaver who moved to Pennsylvania during the American Revolutionary War. He was appointed French consul in Philadelphia and agent for the French Royal Marine in 1778, and in 1780, he became consul general for Pennsylvania, Delaware, New Jersey, and New York. From 1781 to 1784, he pursued private ventures with Robert Morris, the United States Superintendent of Finance and Agent of the Marine. After leaving his official post, Holker partnered with New York-based Parker, Duer & Co. to supply the Continental Army. He established a whiskey distillery with William Duer in Poughkeepsie, New York, and invested with Morris, Duer, and Daniel Parker in the merchant ship Empress of China, an early American vessel engaged in the China trade. Other business partners included William Turnbull and Peter Marmié, with whom he built the Jacobs Creek Iron Works (also known as Alliance Iron Works) in western Pennsylvania in 1789. Married three times, Holker settled in Springsbury, Virginia, after the war.
Custodial History
The John Holker Papers were originally part of the William Smith Mason Collection of Benjamin Franklin, donated to Yale in 1935. The collection was housed in Sterling Memorial Library from 1936 until 1984, when it was transferred to the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.
Related Materials
Associated Materials: Yale Collection of Benjamin Franklin Manuscripts (GEN MSS 1457). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, memoranda, accounts, and invoices relating to the activities of French diplomat and naval agent John Holker during the American Revolutionary War, as well as his private business ventures. Correspondents include Charles-François-Adrien Le Paulmier Annemours, François Barbé-Marbois, Henri-Léonard-Jean-Baptiste Bertin, Jacques-Donatien Le Ray de Chaumont, William Duer, Anne-César de La Luzerne, Peter Marmié, Gouverneur Morris, Robert Morris, Daniel Parker, Mark Pringle, Matthew Ridley, John Ross, William Smith, and William Turnbull. Materials concern supplying the French fleet and army, particularly troops commanded by Jean-Baptiste Donatien de Vimeur; Holker's dealings with Duer, Marmié, Robert Morris, Parker, and Turnbull, and investments in the merchant vessel Empress of China, Jacobs Creek Iron Works, and a whiskey distillery; and trade of American tobacco. Personal bills and invoices in the collection reference people enslaved by Holker. Also included is a card catalog of individual items in the collection, arranged in chronological order.
United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Equipment and supplies; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Finance; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Participation, French; Capitalists and financiers -- United States; Diplomatic and consular service, French -- United States; Diplomats; Iron industry and trade -- United States; Merchants; Shipping -- United States; Slaveholders -- United States; Slavery -- United States; Tobacco industry -- United States -- History; Whiskey industry -- United States; France -- Foreign relations -- United States; United States -- Foreign relations -- France; Annemours, Charles-François-Adrien Le Paulmier, chevalier d', 1742-1809; Barbé-Marbois, François, marquis de, 1745-1837; Bertin, Henri-Léonard-Jean-Baptiste, 1719-1792; Chaumont, Jacques-Donatien Leray de, 1725-1803; Duer, William, 1747-1799; Holker, John, 1745-1822; La Luzerne, Anne-César, chevalier de, 1741-1791; Marmié, Peter; Morris, Gouverneur, 1752-1816; Morris, Robert, 1734-1806; Parker, Daniel, active 1783-1784; Pringle, Mark, -1819; Ridley, Matthew, 1749-1789; Rochambeau, Jean-Baptiste-Donatien de Vimeur, comte de, 1725-1807; Ross, John, 1729-1800; Smith, William, 1728-1814; Turnbull, William, 1751-1822; Empress of China (Ship); France. Armée -- Supplies and stores; France. Marine -- Supplies and stores; Jacobs Creek Iron Works
- Correspondence and Other Papers, 1777–1821; 1; 9.5 Linear Feet (10 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence, memoranda, accounts, bills, invoices, sight drafts, orders, and other papers by or relating to John Holker, his role as agent to the French army and Navy during the American Revolution, and his other business activities. Correspondents include American financiers and agents William Duer, Peter Marmié, Daniel Parker, Mark Pringle, Matthew Ridley, John Ross, William Smith, and William Turnbull; Superintendent of Finance of the United States and Agent of the Marine Robert Morris and Assistant Superintendent of Finance Gouverneur Morris; and Holker's father, French businessman Jean Holker. Also present are correspondence and papers related to French merchants Fizeaux & Cie., Ferdinand Grand, Le Couteulx & Cie., Reculès de Basmarein & Raimbaux, Barthélémy Terrasson, and Roulhac & Cie.; and French diplomats and military officers such as Charles-François-Adrien Le Paulmier Annemours, François Barbé-Marbois, Henri-Léonard-Jean-Baptiste Bertin, Jacques-Donatien Le Ray de Chaumont, Anne-César de La Luzerne, and Jean Baptiste Charles Henri Hector. Materials concern supplying horses, food, and equipment to French troops commanded by Jean-Baptiste Donatien de Vimeur, comte de Rochambeau, in Newport, Rhode Island; shipping interests of the Meulan d'Ablois family; trade of tobacco and indigo; Holker's legal disputes with Duer, Ross, and Smith; and his investments in Empress of China and Jacobs Creek Iron Works. The series also contains a small amount of personal papers documenting Holker's enslavement of at least three people, divorce from his wife Elisabeth, and the settlement of his father's estate.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title, with materials by unidentified authors filed at the end of the sequence.
  - Account of expenses of French consulate in Philadelphia [?], 1785 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accounts related to tobacco, undated (Box 6, Folder 278)
  - Accounts and bills related to shipping, 1779–1781 (Box 6, Folder 279)
    Including the ships Industrie and Marquise de Vienne.
  - Annemours, Charles-François-Adrien Le Paulmier, chevalier d', 1779–1781 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Artois (ship). Account of sales of wine and brandy, account with John Ross, 1788–1790 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ash, James (sheriff). Account with John Holker [related to lawsuits?], 1798 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "B" General, 1780–1787 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Barbé-Marbois, François, marquis de. Memorial to Continental Congress (copy), correspondence, 1784–1785 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Barbé-Marbois, François, marquis de. Orders to Colonel John Mitchell to send wagons to Rhode Island, with invoice for horse teams sent to Rochambeau's troops, 1780 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Barney, Joshua, 1801 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bell, Daniel. Account of disposal of bills of exchange drawn by John Holker on Leray du Chaumont, 1780 (Box 6, Folder 280)
  - Bell, Daniel. Letters to John Holker (with one to Turnbull & Co.), 1778–1780 (Box 6, Folder 281-282)
  - Bertin, Henri-Léonard-Jean-Baptiste, 1779–1780 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Betbeder, Laurent, 1782–1785 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Biddle, Clement (notary public for Pennsylvania), 1813 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Blaine, Ephraim, 1779 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Brétigney, Charles François Sevelinges, marquis de. Authorization to Mr. de Couty to enlist recruits, and proclamation of amnesty to French deserters (copy), 1779 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bunel, [Joseph], 1781–1783 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - Burchell, John Byer, 1780–1786 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Burchell, John Byer. Receipts to Peter Marmié on John Holker's account, 1780–1782 (Box 6, Folder 283)
  - "C" General, 1780–1803 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cabarrus, Leon, 1780–1782 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Caspar Voght & Co., 1783 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cassini, marquise de [Angélique-Dorothée Babaud], 1782 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Chaloner & White, 1779 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Chaumont, Jacques-Donatien Leray, 1778 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Copy of letter to Captain Roche of the ship Union.
  - Chaux de Champeaux, [Pierre], 1788 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Connecticut. General Assembly. Resolution (copy) concerning provisioning of the French Royal Marine, signed by George Wyllys, with letter from Thomas Mumford, 1780 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Constable, Rucker & Co., 1796 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Cotton, Mary, 1778 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "D" General, 1779–1784 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Davis, John. Accounts current with John Holker, memorandum, Holker account with Selles, circa 1780 (Box 6, Folder 284)
  - Davis, John. Certification related to proceedings of the United States District Court for the Massachusetts district, 1817 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Delaville, A. François, 1783 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Diant, Joseph, 1782–1783 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1784–1798 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Dubarras, commandant de l'escadre du Roy, to Anne-César de La Luzerne [extract], circa 1780 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Duer, William
    - Assignment of the cargo of the ship Elephant to John Holker, 1785 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Financial records, 1781–1798 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Letters to John Holker, 1782–1791 (Box 1, Folder 35-37)
    - Letter to Thomas Russell, 1781 (Box 6, Folder 285)
  - Duvergier, V. Leon, Le Boucher & Cie., 1783 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Eguin, Elizabeth, 1786–1787 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Elephant (ship) records, 1784–1785 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Charter party (copy) between James Dunlap and John Laird and Co.; account of valuation of cargo.
  - Empress of China (ship), 1784–1785 (Box 9, Folder 339-340)
  - Espivent de la Villesboisnet, Pierre-Antoine, 1780–1782 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Estaing, Charles Henri, comte d'. Copy of orders to Chevalier de Maty to establish French military hospital in Charleston, 1779 (Box 6, Folder 286)
  - Evans, Benjamin. Certificate of cargoes of rum and taffy on board ships Intéressant, Marie Françoise, and Liverpool, 1780 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Ewing, Thomas, 1781–1782 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "F" General, 1780–1788 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Fizeaux, Grand & Cie., 1780–1784 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Fizeaux, Grand & Cie. Accounts of Maryland tobacco and indigo sales, 1780 (Box 6, Folder 287)
  - Flint, Royal, 1783 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Fooks, Paul, 1780–1781 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - France. Armée
    - Four official reports concerning horses purchased for the artillery of Rochambeau's army, 1780 (Box 6, Folder 288)
    - General statement of expenditures in account with John Holker for Rochambeau's army, 1782 (Box 6, Folder 289-290)
    - Twelve invoices and receipts for use of French troops commanded by Rochambeau at Newport, Rhode Island, July 21-December 26, 1780 (Box 6, Folder 291)
  - France. Marine Royal
    - Copy of bill to ships Intéressant, Marie Françoise, Liverpool, 1780 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Pages removed from ledger, 1781 (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 354)
    - Records of advances, purchases, and expenditures, 1779–1781 (Box 6, Folder 292)
    - Records of provisions shipped by William Smith, 1781 (Box 6, Folder 293-294)
      Includes statement of wheat purchases from John Ward Veazey.
    - "Sundry payments made Messrs. Forman & Chambers, on acct of the purchase of flour & wheat for the Royal Marine", 1781 (Box 6, Folder 295)
  - "G" General, 1779–1782 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Gaillard, Malibran & Cie., 1780 (Box 6, Folder 296-297)
  - Garvey, Anthony, 1785 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Gautier fils, 1780–1783 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Gérard, Conrad Alexandre. Draft circular letter to French consular agents in the United States, 1779 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Gourlade, [Jacques-Alexandre], 1782–1783 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Grand, Ferdinand, 1779–1781 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Grand, Henry, 1778 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Greenway, William. Certificate of cargoes of salt on board Intéressant and Marie Françoise, 1780 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Guignon [?], 1780 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    Copy of letter to an unidentified correspondent concerning a loan to meet expenses of Comte de Estaing's squadron in America.
  - "H" General, 1777–1804 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Hagan, F. [Francis?], 1783 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Harrison (Benjamin) & Co., 1784–1785 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    Includes sight drafts on Thomas Jefferson and James Monroe (signed); shipping invoice to the owners of the Cincinnatus; account current with Holker; receipt to Harrison for military certificates of the state of Virginia.
  - Herries & Co., 1784 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Hewes, Smith & Allen, circa 1780 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Hill, Henry, 1785 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Hobart, Robert E., 1780 (Box 6, Folder 298)
  - Holker, Hughes, 1818 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Holker, Jean [Holker's father], 1779–1783 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Holker, Jean Louis [Holker's son], 1802–1805 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Holker, John
    - Account book, 1779–1782 (Box 7, Folder 300)
    - Account of advances made to Dominique Louis Ethis de Cornis for Rochambeau's carriage, 1780 (Box 7, Folder 301)
    - Account of horses purchased by John Davis for use of the French army, 1780 (Box 9, Folder 341)
    - Accounts, bills, and receipts, 1778–1787 (Box 2, Folder 67-69)
    - Affidavit regarding William Smith's debt, witnessed by William Rush, 1784 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Agreement of arbitration with Augustin Brissault, 1800 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Agreement with Leon Cabarrus, 1779 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Announcement concerning credits to officers and soldiers to offset depreciation in their pay (copy), circa 1780 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Benjamin Harrison & Co. account, 1782 (Box 9, Folder 342)
    - Bond with Samuel C. Peck and John Hopkins to Eben Taylor, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Certified account "Copie de l'etat des avances, faites et remises a Mr. Holker….", 1780 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Correspondence
      Correspondence files sometimes include financial records.
      - To Andrew Craigie, 1789 (Box 2, Folder 76)
      - To Anne-César de La Luzerne [extract, incomplete], circa 1780 (Box 9, Folder 343)
      - To the Board of War, undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
      - To Ethéard [first name unknown] concerning dispute over ship Intéressant, 1780 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      - To Francisco Rendon, 1784 (Box 2, Folder 79)
      - To François de Barbé-Marbois, circa 1780 (Box 7, Folder 302)
      - To George Bond, 1789 (Box 2, Folder 80)
      - To Gouverneur Morris, 1779 (Box 2, Folder 81)
      - To Jacques-Donatien Leray de Chaumont, 1778 (Box 2, Folder 82)
      - To John Davis, 1780 (Box 7, Folder 303)
      - To John Jay, 1779 (Box 2, Folder 83)
      - To [John Mathews], Chairman of the Marine Committee, 1779 (Box 2, Folder 84)
      - To John Ross, 1789–1790 (Box 2, Folder 85)
      - To John Rowe, 1778 (Box 7, Folder 304)
      - To Jolidon [first name unknown], 1779 (Box 2, Folder 86)
      - To Joseph Reed, 1780 (Box 7, Folder 305)
      - To Le Couteulx & Cie., 1783, undated (Box 2, Folder 87)
      - To Mark Pringle, 1785 (Box 2, Folder 88)
      - To Mathias Slough, 1780–1781 (Box 7, Folder 306)
      - To Pelletier [first name unknown], 1778 (Box 2, Folder 89)
      - To Robert Morris, 1784–1786 (Box 7, Folder 307)
      - To St. Seine [first name unknown], 1778 (Box 2, Folder 90)
      - To Thomas FitzSimons, 1792 (Box 2, Folder 91)
      - To Thomas Russell, 1790 (Box 2, Folder 92)
      - to Van Merkel [first name unknown], 1784 (Box 2, Folder 93)
      - To William Duer, 1781 (Box 2, Folder 94)
      - To William Smith, 1787 (Box 2, Folder 95)
      - To William Turnbull, 1780–1781 (Box 2, Folder 96)
      - To unidentified, 1779–1786 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Divorce from Elisabeth Quesnel Holker, 1804 (Box 2, Folder 98)
      Includes correspondence and an opinion from attorney Heron D'Agirône.
    - Financial records, memoranda, other papers [many unidentified], undated (Box 7, Folder 308)
    - General statement of account with Rochambeau's army in America, 1782 (Box 9, Folder 344)
    - Invoice and order for hats and shoes from John Byer Burchell, James Starr, 1780–1787 (Box 2, Folder 99)
      Charges are for servants including Cuff, John Lewis (or Luvis), Henry McCormack. Cuff was likely enslaved by Holker.
    - Jacobs Creek Iron Works partnership agreement with William Turnbull and Peter Marmié, 1790 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Jean Holker estate, 1786 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Lease to John Hoppe, 1804 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - List of loan office certificates, 1789 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Madame V[euve] Thomas account, 1783 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - "Memoire pour M. Holker agent General de la Marine Royale relatif au depot faite d'ordre du [Henry] Messonier [negotiated at] Baltimore", 1781 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Memoranda of belongings, personal expenses, and purchases, 1777–1781 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Memoranda of family property, 1803 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Memorandum containing an order of silver, porcelain, and other items from Jean Baptiste Gradeloup, 1781 (Box 7, Folder 309)
    - Memorandum listing contents of Holker's trunk, 1777 (Box 7, Folder 310)
    - Memorandum relating to the interests of the Meulan d'Ablois family, circa 1779 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Memorandum stating legal aspects of the conduct of Roulhac & Cie. with regard to the interests of the Meulan D'Ablois family, circa 1779 (Box 7, Folder 311)
    - Memorandum stating legal aspects of the conduct of Mr. Terrasson with regard to the interests of Madame de Cassini, 1782 (Box 7, Folder 312)
    - Memorial to Anne-César de La Luzerne regarding interests of the Meulan d'Ablois family (copy), circa 1780 (Box 7, Folder 313)
    - Memorial to Anne-César de la Luzerne regarding the prerogatives of French consular agents (copy), 1779 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Memorial to the President of Congress relating to liquidation of claims against the Marine Royale [draft in unknown hand], circa 1780 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Noel, N. [bills and receipts from family physician], 1780–1781 (Box 2, Folder 111)
      Includes expenses related to an unnamed woman and child enslaved by Holker.
    - [Notes and observations concerning business affairs with Parker, Duer, and Ross], circa 1788 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Notes concerning business affairs between Holker and Robert Morris, 1779 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - "Observations on the answers of Badcock & Joy in Chancery", circa 1787 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Power of attorney to Daniel Bell (draft), 1780 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - "Queries to Comfort Sands", 1784 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Robert Morris
      - Accounts, 1779–1780 (Box 2, Folder 117)
      - "Invoice of Loan Office Certificates delivered to the Honorable John Holker", 1780 (Box 9, Folder 345)
      - Notes and memoranda related to business affairs with Holker, 1784 (Box 9, Folder 346)
    - Sight drafts and promissory notes, 1780–1788 (Box 2, Folder 118-119)
    - Statement of account with M. de Granchain for advances made for the brig Le Cornwallys, 1781 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Thomas Russell account, 1783 (Box 7, Folder 314)
    - William Duer
      - Articles of agreement respecting the distillery at Poughkeepsie, 1781 (Box 7, Folder 315)
      - Holker vs. Duer, 1791–1798 (Box 3, Folder 121-123)
      - Holker vs. Duer, 1798 (Box 7, Folder 316)
      - "Proposition for an amicable settlement of the accounts subsisting between Mr. Duer and Mr. Holker", 1789 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - William Smith lawsuit, 1785–1786 (Box 9, Folder 347-349)
      Includes correspondence with arbitrators Tench Coxe, Matthew Clarkson, and Patrick Moore, Pennsylvania Supreme Court documents related to Holker's suit against Smith.
    - William Trumbull & Co. and Trumbull, Marmié & Co., 1780–1786 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Unidentified, 1801-1804, undated (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Hollingsworth, Levi, 1780–1785 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Hollingsworth, Levi, 1781 (Box 7, Folder 317)
  - Hollingsworth, Zebulon, 1783–1785 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Hope (brig), 1781 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Hoppe, John, 1803–1804 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Hove & Harrison, 1779 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Hunt, John, 1785 (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Inglis (Samuel) & Co., 1781–1782 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - "J-K" General, 1779–1784 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Jean Jacques Bérard & Cie., 1785 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Jean Louis. Bill of sale of Jean Louis, enslaved Black man, to John Holker from Alexandre Heguy, 1780 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Johnston, Robert, 1783 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Josephson, Manuel, 1781 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Keane, Roger, 1782 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - "L" General, 1779–1803 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - La Houssaye, Thomas Marie de. Power of attorney to Jacques-Donatien Leray de Chaumont, 1781 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - La Lande, Jacobus de. Copy of deed from Frederick William Geyer, La Lande, and Hendrick Fyne to George Joy and Daniel Badcock, 1787 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - La Luzerne (ship) account of sales, 1782 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - La Luzerne, Anne-César, chevalier de
    - Authorization to John Holker to travel to Santo Domingo, 1780 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Letters to François Barbé-Marbois, 1782 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Letters to John Holker, 1780–1783 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Lacassagne, M[ichel], 1782–1786 (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Lacaze & Mallet, 1781–1786 (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert Du Motier, marquis de, 1781 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    Copy of note for funds advanced to Lafayette by Jacques-Donatien Leray de Chaumont, through Holker as agent.
  - Lafreté, Jean-Jacques de, 1779–1780 (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - Lane, Son & Fraser, 1790 (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - Le Couteulx & Cie. (Paris), 1781–1784 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    Correspondence related to Empress of China and other matters.
  - Le Couteulx, Joseph Louis and Laurent & Cie. (Cadiz), 1779–1784 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    Letters to Holker, account of recovery of insurance related to abandoned Mexican brig Medusa.
  - Lee, Thomas Sim, 1780 (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - Lemaire [first name unknown]. Testimonial regarding attack on French merchant ship Mary by British frigate, 1779 (Box 3, Folder 155)
  - Lewis, William, circa 1785 (Box 3, Folder 156)
    Regarding dispute between William Duer and Holker.
  - Litter, John. Certificate recounting his capture by British troops in 1777 (copy), 1779 (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - Lively (ship), 1781 (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - Livingston, Henry Brockholst. Certificate of proceedings in the case of van Horne vs. Clarkson and Livingston vs. Frost, 1795 (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - Livingston, Henry Brockholst. Letters to John Holker, 1791 (Box 3, Folder 160)
  - Livingston, Walter. Copy of assignment to William Duer of his share in contract with Robert Morris to supply the army, 1782 (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - Lugnon Jr. [?], 1781 (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - "M" General, 1778–1783 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - Marmié, Peter
    - Deposition concerning his connection with John Holker, undated (Box 3, Folder 163)
    - Letters to John Holker, 1791–1812 (Box 3, Folder 164-165)